Oviedo, Florida (978) 857-3168 CSouthwick@Live.com github.com/csouthwick

# **Profile Summary**

Web developer with over five years of experience creating intuitive and enjoyable user experiences. Emphasis on beautiful, well documented, and modular code for easy maintenance and collaboration. Creative problem solver with a focus on delivering exceptional user experiences that adapt to any screen size.

# **Summary of Qualifications**

- >= 5 yrs Responsive Web Design, (X)HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, PHP, Regex, jQuery, SOAP, C, C++
- < 5 yrs SASS/SCSS, AngularJS, React.JS, ASP.NET, SQL, Node.js</li>
- Adobe Photoshop, Premiere Pro, and After Effects; FFmpeg, x264

# **Core Competencies**

#### Front End Web Development

- Lead designer and sole coder of community TV websites using PHP, SOAP, HTML5, JavaScript, jQuery, AJAX, Responsive Web Design, SASS/SCSS, CSS3, and Schema.org structured data markup
- Enabled the public to view and search TV schedules and watch shows online
- Identified and overcame limitations of the video server's API while improving and expanding site features

## **Technical Support Agent/Case Mentor**

- Maintained 100% customer satisfaction through 200+ surveys resolving hardware and software issues
- Highly praised for impeccable documentation
- Selected for promotion to an elite team to improve site-wide metrics through deep-dive analysis of outliers and engagement with agents and managers on areas of improvement
- Succeeded with our first quarter above 90% customer satisfaction in the program's history

### **Production/Computer Technician**

- Optimized workflow with computer upgrades, maintenance, and troubleshooting
- Achieved a higher quality video and audio experience for viewers and presenters with an overhaul of key
  parts of the studio's equipment and established a roadmap for future upgrades
- Produced, edited, and archived community events, meetings, and shows

# **Professional Work Experience**

Case Mentor/Technical Support Agent	Alorica, account for major PC OEM	2017 - Present
Freelance Web Development and Technical Production/Computer Technician, Web Dev	2015 - 2017	
Georgetown Community Television Rowley Community Media	Georgetown, MA Rowley, MA	2007 - 2015 2012 - 2015

## **Education & Training**

Un	iversity of Massachusetts Lowell	Bachelors in Computer Science	2014
•	Graphic User Interface Programming I & II	(XHTML, HTML5, CSS	, JavaScript, jQuery)

• Computing I,II, III, & IV (C, C++, OOP)